Xavier University Space Committee records
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Xavier University Space Committee records
1964-1987
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Space Committee
.85 linear feet (2 boxes)
This collection contains the agenda and minutes of the Space Committee from December, 1964 to April, 1987, along with other documents and correspondence pertaining to the activities of the committee.
XUA-24
History of Xavier University Space Committee
The Space Committee began on an ad hoc basis in 1964 and continued until January, 1967. In May 1969 the committee was apparently reestablished as a standing committee and served until 1987 when it was discontinued.
The committee was first established in late November, 1964, by Xavier University President Paul O'Connor, with the title "Committee on Allocation of Space." The first meeting was on December 14, 1964. It was set up as an ad hoc committee to study how best to make use of the space "soon to be vacated in various university buildings as a result of the opening of several new buildings on campus." At the final meeting on January 18, 1967, the committee seems to have gone out of existence (see minutes for 1/20/1967). At the suggestion of the Academic Vice President, Jeremiah O'Callaghan, President O'Connor established a university Space Committee which met for the first time on May 19, 1969. It was given the status of a standing committee and was "responsible for the allocation and the use of all space on campus with the exception of those quarters that have been definitely placed under separate and particular jurisdiction by the President." (see 5/19/1969 minutes) Beginning in 1969-70, the Space Committee appeared regularly on the annual list of standing university committees until around 1986-87 when it was discontinued. The 1974-75 Description of Committees gave this information about its charge: "Reporting to the President, the Space Committee reviews all requests for space in University facilities and makes recommendation regarding the renovation of buildings for their more effective use by the University community." Since the beginning of the 2011-12 academic year, the University Planning and Resourcing Council has had a Subcommittee on Space.
Scope and Content
Meeting minutes and related documents from the Xavier University Space Committee.
Statement of Arrangement
Materials are arranged into folders chronologically.
Restrictions on Access
Restricted access. Please contact the Xavier University Archives staff.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Organizations/Corporations:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)-- Buildings; Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)--Planning
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Space Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Space Committee, 1965 February-June (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Space Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Space Committee, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Space Committee, 1969 April-June (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Space Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Space Committee, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Space Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Space Committee, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Space Committee, 1975-1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Space Committee, 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)